## SUMMARY

MSc Data Science Student at EPFL with 5+ years of experience as a Software Engineer. Previously ML engineer at integrate.ai, cofounder at destin.ai, and Next AI entrepreneur. Actively interested in research into the neurosymbolic AI, reasoning, compositionality, linguistically motivated NLP and knowledge-driven, cognitive-model-based

## CONTACT

**™** mismayilza@gmail.com

mete.is

**+**41765051292

**♀** Lausanne, Switzerland

in mismayilzada

nismayil ?

## **SKILLS**

**TECHNOLOGIES** LANGUAGES Python English Turkish Javascript Java Azerbaijani С Russian C++ French HTMI. CSS SQL

node.js Shell scripting Nginx pyspark React.js MongoDB terraform **REST API** pandas Tensorflow matplotlib numpy nltk pytorch sklearn **AWS Services** 

git

## **EDUCATION**

ÉPFL Sep. 2021 to Present

Master Data Science 2023

**University of Waterloo** Sep. 2012 to Jun. 2016

**Bachelor Computer Science 2016** With Distinction

**EMPLOYMENT** 

Sony Inc. Tokyo, Japan Jul. 2022 to Sep. 2022 Research Intern

Research and development of an open-domain dialog system that can mimick any given character based on few utterances

Toronto, Canada integrate.ai Software/ML Engineer Jul. 2019 to Aug. 2021

• Designed and developed core ML infrastructure and tools for Science team to train, test and deploy models

- Collaborated with ML Scientists on research projects to incorporate state of the art ML techniques into our platform
- Designed and developed a Federated Learning framework similar to flower.dev
- Researched and integrated various Differential Privacy techniques into our ML models

Toronto, Canada **Destin AI** Co-founder & CTO Sep. 2017 to Jun. 2019

• End-to-end design and development of the core platform (destin.ai)

- · Built an AI-powered chatbot solution (m.me/heydestin)
- · Participated in Next AI, DMZ, Legal Innovation Zone and MaRS accelerator programs

Toronto, Canada **Bluecat Networks** Sep. 2017 to Jul. 2018 Software Engineer

Enhanced Bluecat's DNS, DHCP and IP solution with various features

Cisco Systems Ottawa, Canada Jun. 2016 to Jul. 2017 Software Engineer

Developed a Python library for programmatic management of Cisco switches and routers

**Freescale Semiconductors** Ottawa, Canada

Software Engineer Intern May 2015 to Aug. 2015

Automated testing and code coverage processes for Linux drivers

**TD Securities** Toronto, Canada

Software Developer Intern May 2014 to Aug. 2014

Developed an accounting web app from end to end

**PROJECTS** 

kogito Feb. 2022 to Jun. 2022

A Knowledge Inference Toolkit

**Differentially Private Random Forest Algorithm** Sep. 2021

Contributed to IBM's differential privacy library diffprivlib

**Words and Personalities** Nov. 2021 to Dec. 2020

Data analysis project exploring the relationship between language and personalities

# METE (MAHAMMAD) ISMAYILZADA

MSC STUDENT

## **AWARDS**

#### Full State Scholarship (2012-2016)

Sep. 2012

Government of Azerbaijan

Full funding during study at University of Waterloo

#### **Certificate of Distinction in the Euclid Mathematics Contest**

Feb. 2012

University of Waterloo

**Presidential Scholarship** 

Sep. 2010

Government of Azerbaijan Awarded to top students entering university studies

## **CERTIFICATES**

#### **NLP Nanodegree**

Udacity

Text Processing, Naive Bayes Classification, Part of Speech Tagging with HMM, Sentiment Analysis, Topic Modelling, RNN, Machine Translation with Deep Learning Attention, Speech Recognition

See credential

#### NLP Specialization (deeplearning.ai)

Coursera

4 courses (Classification and Vector Spaces, Probabilistic Models, Sequence Models, Attention Models)

See credential

#### Machine Learning with Python: From Linear models to Deep Learning (MITx-6.86x)

edX

Classification, Regression, Recommender Systems, Neural Networks, CNN, Clustering, Mixture Models, Reinforcement Learning See credential

#### **Our Privacy Opportunity**

OpenMined

Information Flow, Structured Transparency, Homomorphic Encryption, Secure Multi-party Computation, Differential Privacy

#### Minds and Machines (MITx-24.09x)

edX

 $Chinese\ Room\ Argument,\ Turing\ machines,\ Dualism,\ Functionalism,\ Behavorism,\ Knowledge$ 

See credential

#### Deep Learning Specialization (deeplearning.ai)

Coursera

5 courses (Neural Networks and Deep Learning, Improving Deep Neural Networks, Structuring Machine Learning Projects, Convolutional Neural Networks, Sequence Models)

<u>See credential</u>

## **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **From Words to Vectors**

Article

Published and featured on Towards Data Science

See article